CONTACT



LinkedIn



GitHub



Projects portfolio



pmarcelosilvag@gmail.com

TECHNOLOGIES

Javascript Python C++
PHP HTML5 CSS3
React TailwindCss Bootstrap
NodeJS Sequelize Postsgre
Mysql Express SQL

TECH TOOLS

Github

Vscode

Trello

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Developer – "Academio"

June 2022 - December 2022

Master in Robotics and Automation – "Esneca School" June 2021 - July-2022

B.Sc. in Mechatronics Engineering

– University "Catholica Bolivian
San Pablo"

February 2011 - December 2016

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership
- Team work
- Problem solving
- Decision making
- Results oriented
- Adaptability
- Organizational skills
- Analytical thinking
- Empathy

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: B2

Pablo Marcelo Silva Gutiérrez

Backend Web Developer

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Developer with 4 years of experience in software development, specialized in microcontrolled embedded systems. My passion for technology has led me to obtain postgraduate degrees in automation, mechatronic processes and robotics, which has given me solid skills to design, create and develop software in low and high level languages such as C, C++ and Python. I have applied these skills in diverse areas, such as algorithms for robotics, image processing, internet of things and wireless electronic systems.

Throughout my career, I have successfully led multidisciplinary teams, leading the implementation of projects from conception to delivery. Demonstrating my ability to solve problems and overcome challenges at every step of the process.

As a backend developer, I have demonstrated my skills by specializing as a full-stack web developer at Academlo, a recognized school of computer science. My experience encompasses database management, web application creation from efficient backend to frontend implementation, as well as API creation, data management, and application and database deployment. I also have experience in architecting scalable solutions, ensuring that applications are efficient and ready for growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend development on ID for IDEAS community projects ID for IDEAS (training contract) 3/2023-09/2023

Functions:

- · Relational database design
- REST API development using JavaScript and related NODEjs and Express technologies.
- API's maintenance and troubleshooting.
- WebPack integration for the implementation of external services.
- Implementation and deployment of projects in Railway, Render and configuration and administration of a VPS (Virtual Private Server) in DigitalOcean using Caprover ensuring a secure and efficient environment.
- Detailed documentation of projects and code to facilitate team understanding and collaboration.
- Experience with technologies such as Sequelize for PostgreSQL database manipulation.
- Proficiency in Linux operating systems to effectively manage and configure servers.

Project leader in engineering and embedded software development.

Academy

3/2020-12/2022

- Functions:
 Design and implementation of algorithms in Python language to achieve efficient functionality in specific solutions in image processing.
- Design and creation of algorithms for the development of wireless and mechatronic devices, using C and C++ languages.
- Resolving technical challenges and conflicts during project implementation, maintaining team motivation and productivity.
- Leading teams composed of members with different skills and knowledge to achieve objectives within specific deadlines.

Achievements:

• Successfully developed an algorithm for the navigation of a mobile robot with 90% efficiency.